Scott Higashi

Full Stack Software Engineer

(714) 743.2493 · Scott.M.Higashi@gmai.com · Los Angeles, CA · LinkedIn · GH · Portfolio

As a Software Engineer with a foundation in audio engineering and shipping and handling, I bring a unique blend of technical expertise and operational efficiency. Through my strong work ethic, time management, and communication skills, I will improve workplace efficiency. My goal is to foster a cohesive team environment while driving innovation in full-stack engineering.

SKILLS

Languages - JavaScript, Python | **Libraries and Frameworks** - Node.js, Express.js, React.js

Database - MongoDB, Mongoose, ODM, PostgreSQL | Other - RESTful Routing JSON, CSS, HTML, Postman, Tailwind

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Jun 2023 - Present

Crypto Feed | Responsive website | JavaScript, React.js, HTML, Tailwind CSS

- Developed a full-stack MERN (MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js) application that utilizes APIs to retrieve real-time cryptocurrency data..
- Implemented user authentication and security measures using JSON web tokens (JWT) to protect user data and enhance privacy..
- Styled application using Tailwind CSS.

Portfolio | Responsive website | HTML, CSS, JavaScript

- Created RESTful API fetch calls to an Express, MongoDB, Node.js backend handling all create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations, and tested all backend routes during development using Postman.
- Used Mongoose to define schemas for MongoDB collections.
- Implemented ES6 tagged template literals with Styled-Components along CSS3 to provide style and flexbox layout of the application.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

General Assembly Los Angeles, CA | Remote

Student Student

May 2023 - Aug 2023

- Gained proficiency in a range of languages and technologies, including JavaScript and Python, with hands-on experience using Node.js, Express.js, and React.js to build dynamic web applications.
- Acquired expertise in database design and management using MongoDB, Mongoose, ODM, and PostgreSQL, enabling efficient data storage and retrieval for application functionality.
- Demonstrated skill in implementing RESTful routing, working with JSON, and crafting appealing user interfaces with CSS, HTML, and framworks like Tailwind.

Panda Express Los Angeles, CA

Cook

Mar 2022 - Feb 2023

- Maintained, cleaned, and prepped all produce and equipment, to ensure operations ran smoothly and were completed.
- Cooked all dishes provided on the menu, to ensure optimal customers service and food readily available.

Kitchen Help

Mar 2021 - Mar 2022

- Maintained, cleaned, and prepped all produce and equipment, to ensure operations ran smoothly and were completed.
- Cooked side dishes, such as, chow mein and fried rice, to ensure optimal customers service and food readily available.
- Provided customer service to all guests, to ensure all customers had a satisfying experience.

UPS Anaheim, CA

Air Operations Supervisor

Dec 2015 - Oct 2016

- Maintained, managed, and delegated store operational procedures on a day-to-day basis, to ensure daily operations were completed.
- Supervised and implemented security and loss prevention on up to 15 employees, to ensure safety and general protocols were practiced.
- Trained employees to follow safety procedures in accordance with Company, OSHA, and DOT guidelines, to have minimal injuries.
- Prepared action plans to ensure the service center achieves planned productivity, load average, cube utilization, and service targets.

Load/Sort Operations Supervisor

Apr 2015 - Dec 2015

- Managed up a group of up to 33 employees to monitor accuracy and quality of loading and sorting packages, to be delivered correctly to all operation belts..
- Applied leadership and analytical skills to execute company and personal goals.

Package Sorter Nov 2014 - Apr 2015

• Sorted boxes by color code, zipcode, and area code to different conveyors, to ensure all packages were sent to correct sending trailers.

• Insured packages are moved keeping customer satisfaction in mind.

EDUCATION

GENERAL ASSEMBLY | REMOTE

Software Engineering Immersive

May 2023 - August 2023

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

SAE INSTITUTE | LOS ANGELES, CA

Audio Engineer '18 Class Valedictorian

Jan 2017 - Jan 2018

Audio technology program that specialized in sound engineering, post production, studio production, recording engineer, and live sound. Received audio technology diploma.